<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on Jordan B. Kinder</title>
    <link>https://jbkinder.github.io/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on Jordan B. Kinder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Jordan B. Kinder</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 16:19:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jbkinder.github.io/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Postcapitalisms—Good and Bad</title>
      <link>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/postcapitalisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 16:19:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/postcapitalisms/</guid>
      <description>McKenzie Wark’s Capital is Dead: Is This Something Worse? (2019) is built on a controversial wager in many Marxist circles. The wager is that capitalism, regardless of adjectives, is no longer the dominant mode of production. We’ve transitioned from capitalism to, well, “something worse,” as the subtitle&amp;rsquo;s open provocation suggests. This political economic arrangement gathered under the signifier of “something worse” emerges from the reality that the dominant class is no longer that class that owns material means of production, but rather, information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Infrastructure and The Criminalization of Indigenous Resistance</title>
      <link>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/critical-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:19:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/critical-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>I read Andrew Crosby and Jeffrey Monaghan&amp;rsquo;s Policing Indigenous Movements: Dissent and the Security State at the same time that I was teaching about the relationship between infrastructural development, settler colonialism, and what Leanne Betasamosake Simpson and others name &amp;ldquo;Indigenous resurgence&amp;rdquo;1 in an undergraduate research course on energy, culture, and environment. What initially struck me about Crosby and Monaghan&amp;rsquo;s account was the ease in which it ties together mutually informing problems of the legacies of settler colonialism, the rise of the surveillance state, extractivism as a dominant modality, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>