<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jordan B. Kinder</title>
    <link>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jordan B. Kinder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Jordan B. Kinder</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 16:19:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jbkinder.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief Tutorial for Enabling Flash in Chrome</title>
      <link>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/flash-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 16:19:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/flash-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Prezi uses Adobe Flash Player, which is disabled by default in most web browsers. If you are having trouble enabling Adobe Flash Player in Google Chrome, see the brief instructions I&amp;rsquo;ve put together below. If you are using Safari, please follow the instructions in Adobe&amp;rsquo;s tutorial linked here. Adobe also has detailed instructions for Chrome, Safari, and Firefox here.
If you see this screen when trying to open the remote Prezi: Click the lock symbol beside the URL bar and choose &amp;ldquo;Allow,&amp;rdquo; then reload/refresh the page: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Infrastructure and The Criminalization of Indigenous Resistance</title>
      <link>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/critical-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:19:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbkinder.github.io/post/critical-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>I read Andrew Crosby and Jeffrey Monaghan&amp;rsquo;s Policing Indigenous Movements: Dissent and the Security State at the same time that I was teaching about the relationship between infrastructural development, settler colonialism, and what Leanne Betasamosake Simpson and others name &amp;ldquo;Indigenous resurgence&amp;rdquo;1 in an undergraduate research course on energy, culture, and environment. What initially struck me about Crosby and Monaghan&amp;rsquo;s account was the ease in which it ties together mutually informing problems of the legacies of settler colonialism, the rise of the surveillance state, extractivism as a dominant modality, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>